# Jake Zimmermann

T: 07545128394

E: jake\_zimmermann@hotmail.co.uk

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jake-zimmermann-66776339/

Github CV: https://github.com/JakeOtto



## Personal Profile

Freshly graduated student of Makers academy, studying Data Engineering whilst working as a WordPress developer for a few small-scale clients. Hard working with excellent problem-solving skills, strong observational/ collaborative skills, and quick hands-on learner, these skills have allowed me to pursue private projects both by myself and within a small team but have led me longing to develop a more substantial career in Data engineering. Previous experience in management roles has led to well-developed teamwork skills and good communicator habits, keen to help others in both work and community projects. Also, developing my ai interaction skills and a weekend greengrocer at Barnet market since 2007, which has led to great client facing communication skills and a fond, kind-hearted attitude to community interaction.

## Experience

## **Proof Of Treasure – Private project**

January 2022 - Present

- https://proofoftreasure.com
  - Developing programming skills with Chialisp (token transactions).
  - Building discord.py bots for community/staff interactions allowing more efficient team task management.
  - Public game creation methods as well as accuracy checks.
  - Working with a small developer team.

## WordPress developer/teacher – Barnet Market

December 2021 – Ongoing

- https://barnet-market.co.uk
- Working with clients in person helping them develop skills for their own personal site maintenance and improvements.

## WordPress developer – The After 30s Podcast

July 2020 - September 2021

- Managing, testing and optimising TA30s website using Google Analytics.
- Managing and implementing new content with WordPress CMS.
- Reporting bugs and suggesting improvements of the website to clients.
- Providing monthly website reports highlighting key metrics and on-site opportunities.
- Competitor research.
- On-site SEO.

#### IT support technician - London Metropolitan University

November 2017 - October 2019

- Managing accounts and providing first and second line support to the university students and faculty members.
- Working with system administration tools.
- Personal and group face to face support meetings.
- Working as part of a larger team.

## Development Tools & Languages

## **Development tools**

Visual Studio, Bluestacks, Eclipse, Glassfish, NetBeans, Slack, GitHub, Android Studio, GCP, React, Pytest, AWS, Docker, Flask, RDBs, S3, EC2, AWS Lambda, Kafka, Kaggle

#### Languages used

Java, JavaScript, Python, CSS, PHP, Chialisp, SQL

#### Education

## Makers Academy - Data engineering specialization

Sept 04 - January 14th, 2024

TDD and Object-Oriented-Programming focused in Python (agile, waterfall and free flowing development)

SQL and data processing

Data analysis and presenting insights

Data warehouse modelling

Git source control

AWS Services, RDBs, EC2s, Lambda, S3 Buckets

Apache Airflow and DAG design

#### Charity/ Personal Experiences

- Teaching Math and PE Namanga Christian School, Kenya.
- Teaching, site construction Brothers of the Sacred Heart Zambia.
- Volunteer chef Paradise Parks kids' community centre.
- Development of personal languages, German, Mandarin.
- Mathematics revision centre popup mathematics revision centre, leaning business opening legalities and teaching skills.
- Coaching 2 years coaching in a popular e-sport, developing my confidence in making a viable career from a personal hobby. Further improving my communication skills through explaining concepts clearly and well to customers.
- London Youth Olympics three years Volleyball representative for Barnet, developing teamwork skills. Previously playing rugby for Saracen's youth teams too.
- Management roles -
  - Restaurant manager Bufle, Rupert Street W1
  - Payrole, delegation, licencing, site management requirements, HR roles Duty manager Q.E. Girls sport centre
  - Delegation, rota/schedule management, staff teaching